Guide to the Herbert Scarf papers, 1951-2015 RL.11619
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Research and Notes, 1951-2015; 3
  - Writings by Others
    - Unindexed: D-K, 1960s-2000s; 15 folders (Box 12)
    - Unindexed: K-S, 1960s-2000s; 19 folders (Box 13)
    - Unindexed: S-Z, 1970s-2000s; 12 folders (Box 14)
- Writings, 1952-2009; undated; 4
  This series contains copies, reprints, drafts, notes, and other documents associated with Scarf's published works. These include: reprints and copies of published journal articles and book chapters; contributions to festschrift volumes; and documents from his referee activity for academic journals and publishers.
  - 1975 Nobel Prize in Economics: Resource Allocation (Box 6)
    Reprint and files related to article on award of Nobel to Koopmans and Kantorovich
  - Algorithm for a Class of Nonconvex Programming Problems, 1966-1968 (Box 6)
    Discussion paper, drafts, and related correspondence
  - Allocation of Resources in the Presence of Indivisibilities, 1994 (Box 6)
    Reprint, discussion paper, drafts, and related correspondence
  - Analysis of Markets with a Large Number of Participants, 1961-1972; 2 folders (Box 6)
    Copy of conference volume Recent Advances in Game Theory published for participants, discussion paper, drafts, and related correspondence
  - Approximate Solutions to a Simple Multi-Echelon Inventory Problem, 1962 (Box 6)
    Reprint
  - Approximation of Fixed Points of a Continuous Mapping, 1967-1970; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Bayes Solutions of the Statistical Inventory Problem, 1959-1975 (Box 6)
    Reprint and related correspondence
  - Comment on: M. Hirota, 1980-1981; 2 folders (Box 6)
    Draft and related correspondence for comment on "On the Stability of Competitive Equilibrium and the Patterns of Initial Holdings: An Example"
  - Complex of Maximal Lattice Free Simplices, 1994 (Box 6)
    Reprint, drafts, discussion paper, and related correspondence
  - Computation and Modelling of Economic Equilibria, 1987 (Box 6)
    Draft and related correspondence for Preface to volume edited by A.J.J. Talman and G. van der Laan
  - Computation of Competitive Prices in a General Equilibrium Model, undated (Box 6)
    Draft
  - Computation of Economic Equilibria, 1971-1974; 2 folders (Box 6)
    Correspondence related to the publication of book with Terje Hansen
  - Computation of Equilibrium Prices: An Exposition (CFDP 473) Chapter in Handbook of Math. Economics, 1982 (Box 6)
  - Computation of Equilibrium Prices: An Exposition (CFDP 473) Chapter in Handbook of Math. Economics, 1982; 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Computation of General Equilibria: An Essay for the New Palgrave Encyclopedia, 1983-1988; 2 folders (Box 15)
    Copy of published version, drafts, and related correspondence
  - Computing Price Equilibria of Linear Economic Models, undated (Box 15)
  - Core of an N Person Game, 1967-1968 (Box 15)
  - Discrete Maximization, 1975 (Box 15)
  - Dynamic Theory of Consumer's Choice, 1959-1971 (Box 15)
  - Early Integer Programming, undated (Box 15)
  - Economic Equilibrium and Soviet Economic Reform, 1991 (Box 15)
  - Elementary Proof of a Theorem on the Core of an N Person Game, undated (Box 15)
  - Equilibrium Points of Two Person Games and the Brouwer Fixed Point Theorem, undated (Box 15)
  - Example of an Algorithm for Calculating General Equilibrium Prices, 1969 (Box 15)
  - Exploration of a Stability Concept for Armed Nations, 1967 (Box 15)
  - Fixed-Point Theorems and Economic Analysis, 1983 (Box 15)
    Published version
  - Foreword to Applied General Equilibrium and Economic Development, 1992 (Box 15)
    Copy of published version and related correspondence
  - Froebenius Problem and Maximal Lattice Free Bodies, 1993 (Box 15)
  - Games with Partial Information, 1957 (Box 15)
  - Generalized Basis Reduction Algorithm, 1992 (Box 15)
  - Generating Functions and MLFBS, undated (Box 15)
  - Group Invariant Integration and the Fundamental Theorem of Algebra, 1952 (Box 15)
  - Herbert Scarf, Growth Stories of the Economists, 2001 (Box 15)
    Published version in Chinese
  - Implementation of the Generalized Basis Reduction Algorithm for Integer Programming, 1993 (Box 15)
    Reprint, discussion paper, and related correspondence
  - Integral Polyhedra in Three Space, 1982 (Box 15)
  - Integral Polyhedra in Three Space, 1985 (Box 14)
    Handwritten draft and notes
  - Introduction to Fixed Points: Algorithms and Applications, 1977 (Box 15)
  - Inventory Models and Related Stochastic Processes, 1958 (Box 15)
    Copy of published version
  - Inventory Models of the Arrow-Harris-Marschak Type with Time Lag, 1958 (Box 15)
  - Inventory Problems with Random Lead Times, undated (Box 15)
  - Inventory Theory, 2002 (Box 15)
  - Karlin Festschrift, 1988-1990 (Box 15)
    Reprint, drafts, and related correspondence for contribution, A Theorem in Search of a Simple Proof, to volume in honor of Samuel Karlin
  - Koopmans Memoirs, 1975-1995 (Box 15)
    Reprint, drafts, and related correspondence for biographical memoir of Tjalling Koopmans published by the National Academy of Sciences
  - Limit of the Core of an Economy, 1970-1972 (Box 15)
    Reprint, drafts, and related correspondence
  - Limit Theorem on the Core of an Economy, 1963-1966 (Box 15)
    Reprint, includes French translation
  - Mathematical Programming and Economic Theory, 1990 (Box 15)
    Published version, reprint, discussion paper, draft, and related correspondence
  - Matrices with Identical Sets of Neighbors, 1998 (Box 15)
    Reprint and discussion paper
  - Maximization of an Integral Subject to Constraints, 1955 (Box 15)
    Working paper
  - Min-Max Solution of an Inventory Problem, 1958 (Box 15)
  - Neighborhood Complexes and Generating Functions for Affine Semigroups, 2006 (Box 15)
  - Neighborhood Systems for Production Sets with Indivisibilities, 1983-1986 (Box 15)
  - Note on Stochastic Processes with plus-minus 1 Variate, 1953 (Box 16)
  - Notes on the Core of a Productive Economy, 1963-1986 (Box 16)
    Reprint, drafts, and notes
  - Notes on the Use of a Class of Algorithms (Part 1), undated (Box 16)
  - Observation on the Structure of Production Sets with Indivisibilities, 1977; 2 folders (Box 16)
    Reprint, discussion paper, drafts, notes, and related correspondence
  - On the Application of a Recent Combinatorial Algorithm, 1968; 2 folders (Box 16)
  - On the Computation of Equilibrium Prices, 1967 (Box 16)
    Copy of published version, discussion paper, drafts, and related correspondence
  - On Cores and Indivisibility, 1972-1974 (Box 16)
    Copy of published version, working paper, drafts, and related correspondence
  - On Differential Games with Survival Payoff, 1957 (Box 16)
    Reprint and copy of draft
  - On the Existence of a Cooperative Solution for a General Class of N-Person Games, 1970-1992; 2 folders (Box 16)
    Reprint, discussion paper, drafts, related correspondence, and 1992 re-publication
  - Optimal Inventory Planning When Sales are Discretionary, 2005 (Box 16)
  - Optimal Policies for a Multi-Echelon Inventory Problem, 1960; 2004; 2 folders (Box 16)
    Reprint and 50th anniversary re-publication
  - Optimality of (S,s) Policies in the Dynamic Inventory Problem, 1959; 1993; 2 folders (Box 16)
    Reprint, discussion paper, drafts, related correspondence, and republished version
  - Origins of Fixed Point Methods, 1991 (Box 16)
    Copy of published version, draft, and related correspondence
  - Outline of Some Results on Production and the Core, undated (Box 16)
  - Preface to Proceedings of Conference on Economic Equilibria: Computation and Modelling, 1986-1987 (Box 16)
    Drafts and related correspondence
  - Production Sets with Indivisibilities Part 1, 1979-1981; 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Production Sets with Indivisibilities: The Case of Two Activities / Part 2, 1980-1981 (Box 16)
    Reprint, draft, and related correspondence
  - Recursive Argument for K-Concavity, 2000 (Box 16)
  - Refereeing and Reviewing, 1987-2001 (Box 16)
    Includes referee reports and associated correspondence with editors
  - Remark on Quinzii's Proof that the Matching Problem Leads to a Balanced Game, 2009 (Box 16)
  - S,s Rule is an Optimal Trading Strategy in a Class of Commodity Price Speculation Problems, 2000 (Box 16)
  - Scarf Selected Papers / Kehoe, 1994-2001 (Box 16)
    Copy of published version, drafts, related correspondence, and other documents for collected volume Scarf's papers
  - Shaped Sources for Teletherapy Units, 1953 (Box 16)
  - Shapes of Polyhedra, 1988-1990; 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Shortest Integer Vectors, 1993 (Box 16)
  - Solution of Systems of Piecewise Linear Equations, 1975-1976 (Box 17)
  - Some Additional Remarks to "Notes on the Core", 1963 (Box 17)
  - Some Examples of Global Instability of the Competitive Equilibrium, 1960 (Box 17)
  - Some Remarks on Bayes Solutions to the Inventory Problem, 1960 (Box 17)
  - Survey of Analytic Techniques in Inventory Problems, 1963 (Box 17)
  - Test Sets for Integer Programs, 1997 (Box 17)
  - Testing for Optimality in the Absence of Convexity, 1984-1986 (Box 17)
  - Thesis, 1954 (Box 17)
    Copy of Scarf's doctoral thesis titled "Differential Operators on Manifolds, and Applications to Stochastic Processes", and related notes
  - Topological Structure of Maximal Lattice Free Convex Bodies: The General Case, 1994 (Box 17)
    Discussion paper and draft
  - Two New Proofs of Afriat's Theorem, 2004 (Box 17)
  - Unimodular Matrices and a Covering Problem, 1972 (Box 17)
  - Uniqueness of Equilibrium in the Multi-Country Ricardo Model, 2003 (Box 17)
    Discussion paper
  - von Neumann Model, undated (Box 17)
    Draft and notes for paper titled "Some Suggestions for Computing the von Neumann Path of Maximal Proportional Growth"
- Academia, 1957-2015; undated; 5
  Includes teaching materials, committee, departmental, and other work for Scarf's professorship at Yale and the Cowles Foundation.
  - Applied Mathematics, 1988 (Box 17)
    Includes documents related to Yale's applied math graduate program
  - Computer Information - Misc., 1988-1990 (Box 17)
  - Cowles Foundation, 1964-2015 (Box 17)
    Includes files related to Scarf's service as Director of Cowles
  - Cowles Foundation: Director's Fund, 1982-1989 (Box 17)
  - Dean of Graduate School Search Committee, 1997 (Box 17)
    Includes files related to service as committee member
  - Discrete Math Program, 1987-1997 (Box 17)
    Includes files related to Yale's discrete mathematics program
  - Economics Department, 1985-2009 (Box 17)
    Includes files for routine department business
  - Economics Department: Annual Activities Report, 1968-1997 (Box 17)
    Includes copies of Scarf's annual reports summarizing professional activities
  - Economics Department: Dissertations, 1979 (Box 17)
    Includes files related to serving on dissertation committees
  - Grad Search Committee, 1990-1993; 2 folders (Box 17)
    Includes files related to search for dean of Yale's graduate school
  - Jonathan Edwards College, 1992-1996 (Box 17)
    Includes files related to service as faculty advisor to students of the college
  - Master Search Committee - Jonathan Edwards College, 1991-1996; 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Math-Econ Seminar, 1986 (Box 17)
  - Montias Material, 1996 (Box 17)
    Includes files related to faculty meeting tribute to Michael Montias
  - Scarf: Leave of Absence, 1969-1970; 1980-1981; 1985-1986; 3 folders (Box 17)
  - Scarf: Job Offers, 1962-1987 (Box 17)
  - Scarf: Yale Committees, 1975-1987 (Box 17)
    Includes files for service on various committees
  - Scholarships and Student Aid, 1991 (Box 17)
    Includes promotional materials
  - Search Committee - Dean, Music School, 1988-1992 (Box 17)
  - Sterling Grant, 1991-1994 (Box 17)
    Includes files related to grant funding
  - Yale: Appointments, 1963-1995 (Box 17)
  - Yale: College, 1991-1999 (Box 17)
    Includes files for various routine matters
  - Yale: Graduate School, 1992-1998 (Box 17)
    Includes files for routine business within the graduate school
  - Yale: Honorary Degrees, 1995 (Box 17)
  - Yale: Restructuring, 1989-1992 (Box 17)
  - Yale: School of Organization & Management, 1975-1997 (Box 17)
    Includes files for routine business within the School of Oragnization and Management
  - Yale: Tribunal, 1969-1974 (Box 17)
    Includes files for proposed university-wide tribunal
  - Yale: Tricentential Planning Committee, 1990 (Box 17)
  - Letters of Recommendation: A, 1964-1994; 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Letters of Recommendation: F-Z, 1964-1998; 8 folders (Box 18)
  - Applied Math 450a (Discrete Mathematics, Integer Programming and Lattice Theory), 1987; 2 folders (Box 18)
  - ECON 35b (Topics in Mathematical Economics I), 1975 (Box 18)
    Includes lecture notes
  - ECON 100, 1971 (Box 18)
    Includes files for computer use
  - ECON 107 (Mathematical Economics), 1967-1971; 3 folders (Box 18)
    Includes lecture notes and sample assignments and exams
  - ECON 107a (Mathematical Economics), 1975-1976; 2 folders (Box 18)
  - ECON 107b (Mathematical Economics), 1972; 1977; 2 folders (Box 18)
    Includes sample exams
  - ECON 109 (Topics in Mathematical Economics II), 1971-1972 (Box 18)
  - ECON 120 (Economic Statistics), 1972 (Box 18)
    Includes sample assignments and exams
  - ECON 155 (Mathematical Economics I), 2005 (Box 18)
    Includes syllabus and other course documents
  - ECON 155a (Mathematical Economics I), 1984 (Box 14)
  - ECON 155a, 156b (Mathematical Economics I, II), 1990-1993 (Box 18)
  - ECON 156b (Mathematical Economics II), 1991 (Box 18)
    Includes lecture notes and syllabi
  - ECON 500a (Microeconomic Theory), 1988; 1994-1995; 2 folders (Box 18)
    Includes sample assignments and exams, and course syllabi (including iteration co-taught with Truman Bewley)
  - ECON 500a (Microeconomic Theory), 1988 (Box 14)
  - ECON 501 (Microeconomic Theory, undated (Box 14)
  - ECON 501a, 501b (Microeconomic Theory), 1994-1997 (Box 18)
    Includes sample assignments and exams, as well as lecture notes
  - ECON 501b (Microeconomic Theory), 1994-1997; 4 folders (Box 18)
    Includes sample assignments and exams, as well as syllabi and lecture notes
  - ECON 526b (Discrete Mathematics, Integer Programming and Lattice Theory), 1990 (Box 19)
    Includes syllabus
  - ECON 530, undated (Box 14)
  - ECON 530a (Mathematical Economics), 1978-1986; 3 folders (Box 19)
    Includes syllabi, sample exams, and lecture notes
  - ECON 531b (Mathematical Economics II), 1980-1996; 4 folders (Box 19)
  - ECON 532a (Workshop in Economic Theory and Mathematical Economics, 1979 (Box 19)
    Includes lectures notes
  - ECON 532b (Applied General Equilibrium), 1992 (Box 19)
    Includes syllabus and lecture notes
  - ECON 537a/538b (Seminar on Discrete Math and its Applications), 1986-1987 (Box 19)
    Includes course schedule and syllabus
  - Economic Theory Seminar, 1965-1966 (Box 19)
    Includes schedule
  - Miscellaneous Reading Lists, 1985 (Box 19)
    Includes reading lists for courses taught by other faculty members
  - OR/MS 526a (Discrete Mathematics, Integer Programming and Lattice Theory), 1987 (Box 19)
  - STAT 116, 1957 (Box 19)
    Includes lecture notes, as well as sample assignments and exams for course taught at Stanford
  - Queues, undated (Box 19)
  - Scarf's Lecture Notes, undated; 2 folders (Box 19)
    Compilation of lecture notes over various topics
  - Lecture Notes: General Equilibrium and Fixed Points, undated (Box 14)
    Includes hand-written lecture notes
  - Lecture Notes: Mathematical Economics, 1983; undated; 6 folders (Box 20)
    Includes hand-written notes, presentation materials, and other documents related to various lectures on mathematical economics
  - Lecture Notes: Operations Research, undated; 7 folders (Box 20)
    Includes hand-written notes, presentation materials, and other documents related to various lectures on operations research
  - Math Econ Workshop, 1981 (Box 20)
  - Misc. Lecture Notes, undated (Box 20)
    Includes various unlabeled lecture notes
  - Notes for Integer Programming Course at Stanford, 1978 (Box 20)
  - OR 526b (Discrete Mathematics, Integer Programming and Lattice Theory), undated (Box 20)
- Personal, 1963-2011; undated; 6
  Contains biographical materials, photographs, and other personal documents.
  - Bibliography / Vita, 1974-1992 (Box 21)
    Includes copies of vita and various biographical questionnaires
  - Distinguished Fellow - AEA (American Economic Association), 1992 (Box 21)
    Includes documents related to Scarf being named a distinguished fellow of the association
  - Economic Theory Fellow, 2011 (Box 21)
    Includes award certificate from the Society for the Advancement of Economic Theory
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1977-2006 (Box 21)
    Includes various newspaper clippings, mostly articles by Maggie Scarf
  - Personal, 1963-1996 (Box 21)
    Includes documents and correspondence related to employment, as well as other personal items
  - Personal Notes, 2009 (Box 21)
    Includes various personal notes
  - Photographs, 1991; undated (Box 21)
    Includes various official portraits taken by Yale University